Alright, also now let's do this with TypeScript.
好的，现在让我们使用 TypeScript 来进行操作
So I am going to go ahead and just start this from our JavaScript section.
我将直接从我们的 JavaScript 部分开始来继续操作
However, if in the future, you want to start a new Hardhead project,
但如果将来你打算开始一个新的 Hardhat 项目
you can actually start a new project with yarn, hard hat.
那么你可以这样操作 "yarn hardhat"
And then do great and advanced sample project that uses TypeScript,
然后选择 "Create an advanced sample project that uses TypeScript"
(“使用 TypeScript 创建一个高级示例项目”)
you'll add a ton of plugins. And you'll wait a while for everything to get uploaded.
它会添加大量插件，你需要稍等一段时间直到所有内容上传完毕
And you wait, and you wait a little bit for everything to get downloaded.
然后再稍微等一会儿直到所有内容下载完成
We're not going to do that though,
我们并不会这样做
because I'm going to show you how to convert this to JavaScript Anyways,
因为我将向你展示如何把这个转换为 JavaScript (口误，应为 TypeScript)
if in future hearted sections, as we're coding along with JavaScript,
在未来的 Hardhat 部分，我们仍会采用 JavaScript 来编写代码
if you want to code along with TypeScript, you absolutely 100% can.
但如果你想用 TypeScript 的话，也是百分百可以的
But let's go ahead and show you what the main differences are.
现在让我来向你展示它们之间的主要差别是什么
Now that advanced TypeScript thing is going to add a whole bunch of packages that you may or may not want,
现在，这个高级 TypeScript 选项添加了一大堆你可能用的到也可能用不到的包
I will talk about some of them in our next lesson.
我会在下节课中讨论其中的某些
But there are going to be some that you absolutely do need.
但有几个是你肯定会用到的
Those are going to be at type chain slash ethers, dash v five, at type chain, slash hard hat,
它们是 "@typechain/ethers-v5 @typechain/hardhat"
at TypeScript, at types, slash Chai, at types, slash node, at types slash moko,
"@types/chai @types/node @types/mocha"
TS node, type chain and TypeScript.
"ts-node typechain" 以及 "typescript"
And I have a link in the GitHub repo associated with this course,
我在课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中提供了一个链接
I've got this yarn ad that you can just copy paste,
这里有一个 "yarn add" 后面的你可以直接复制粘贴
if you want to just copy paste that into your project to run it.
如果你想的话可以直接把它们复制粘贴到你的项目中运行
Oops, and I should have added those as dev dependencies.
哎呀，我还应该把它们添加到 "devDependencies" 里
So we're going to actually just make them dev dependencies real quick,
我们可以很快地把它们放进 "devDependencies" 里
just by deleting these two lines, and adding a comma here.
只要删除这两行，然后添加一个逗号就行了
Awesome, that looks much better.
不错，看起来好多了
And then of course, what we're going to do is we're going to convert all of our JavaScript to TypeScript.
当然，接下来要做的就是把 JavaScript 转换到 TypeScript 了
So anywhere where we have J S, we're going to put Ts,
所以只要是 "js" 的地方，一律替换成 "ts"
obviously, if you're coding this from scratch with TypeScript,
显然，如果你是从头使用 TypeScript
you would do the.ts From the get go.
这里就要直接写成 ".ts"
This includes our hard hat dot config, that's also going to be TypeScript now.
包括我们的 "hardhat.config"，现在也变成 TypeScript 了
And additionally, we're going to add a TS config dot JSON.
此外我们还要添加一个 "tsconfig.json"
This is going to be our TypeScript configuration.
这是我们的 TypeScript 配置文件
Typically, for a setup, we're gonna go with something like this.
通常情况下，我们会采用类似这样的配置
And you can copy this from the GitHub repo associated with this course.
你可以直接从课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中复制它们
It's basically telling TypeScript,
基本上它就是告诉 TypeScript
what versions of Typescript and what files to include for working with TypeScript.
要使用哪个版本的 TypeScript 以及哪些文件被用于处理 TypeScript
Now let's go ahead and start with our deploy dot TypeScript.
现在让我们开始处理我们的 "deploy.ts" 文件
For usual, instead of using require,
通常情况下，我们不再使用 "require"
we're gonna go ahead and use import,
而是使用 "import"
we're gonna do the exact same thing.
我们要做的事情差不多
We're gonna have import ethers run network, from hard hat.
输入 "import  from "hardhat""
And then in our verify function, we're going to add that we're gonna add the types for these arguments.
然后在我们的 "verify" 函数中，我们要给这些参数添加数据类型
So contract address, is going to be a string.
"contractAddress" 是一个 "string"
And args is going to be an array of arguments.
而 "args" 则是包含参数的一个数组
So we're gonna say it's gonna be any array,
所以我们会说它是一个 "any[]"
because it could be string, it could be numbers, it could be balloons, it could be anything.
因为它既可以是一个字符串也可以是一个数字或者布尔值，它可以是任何类型
We're also going to say for IE, it could be any,
我们还要把 "e" 指定为 "any" 类型
even though this is technically an error type,
尽管从技术上来说它是一个 "Error" 类型
we're just going to put any for simplicity. For now.
但为了简单起见，我们现在把它设置为 "any" 就好
All of our TypeScript scripts are included in our TS config,
我们所有的 TypeScript 脚本都会包含进我们的 "tsconfig" 中
or any TypeScript files are manually added here,
或者任何 TypeScript 文件也可以手动添加在这里
which we have Our entire scripts folder here, which is good.
我们在这里放入了整个 "scripts" 文件夹，这很不错
So now we need to add ethers in here.
现在我们要在这里添加 "ethers" 了
Well, if we look at our hardhead.config.ts, we're using require here still,
如果我们看一下我们的 "hardhat.config.ts"，这里使用的仍然是 "require"
and we need to swap this out for import
我们需要把它们替换成 "import"
for Donnie V, you can use dot env slash config for it to grab your dot env file.
对于 "dotenv"，你可以使用 "dotenv/config" 来获取你的 ".env" 文件
Now that we've imported everything, go back to our deploy.ts,
现在我们已经把所有东西都导入好了，回到我们的 "deploy.ts"
we can see that that linting has gone away.
可以看到刚才的报错已经消失了
If you want to be even more explicit,
如果你想表达的更明确
we can go ahead and add import at nomic labs slash hard hat ethers like so.
那么可以添加 "import @nomiclabs/hardhat-ethers"，就像这样
reason we don't need to import it here is because these two packages also work with Hardhead ethers,
之所以不用在这导入它是因为这两个包也使用 "hardhat-ethers"
so they automatically import it. But if you want to be super explicit,
所以它们会自动导入它，但如果你特别想表达明确
you can go ahead and add it like so.
就可以像这样把它添加进来
Now, we're almost good to go.
现在我们可以继续前进了
But remember, our Harnett dot config is also importing our tasks.
但记住，我们的 "hardhat.config" 同时还导入了我们的 tasks
So we're going to need to update our tasks or block number to be TypeScript fide.
所以我们需要把我们的 tasks 或者说 "block-number" 更新为 TypeScript 格式
So of course, instead of const require, we're going to import task from our that slash config.
所以说当然，不再是 "const require"，要改成 "import  from "hardhat/config""
And we're going to be sure to export our task from lock number as the default.
并且我们要确保 "block-number" task 要导出为 "default"
So we're going to do export default task like so.
所以我们要写成 "export default task" 就像这样
And now we should be good to run our scripts.
现在应该就能运行我们的脚本了
So we can just do yarn, art hat, run scripts, employee.ts.
只要执行 "yarn hardhat run scripts/deploy.ts"
We can do network hard hat if we choose. And awesome.
如果需要的话还可以加上 "--network hardhat"，好极了
Now, it's when we get to the testing, that things get a little bit different here.
现在，轮到我们的测试环节了，这里的情况会有些不同
So let's go ahead and change this required to import.
我们先把这里的 "require" 改成 "import"
Just to make it happy there.
为的是让它不要报错
Let's try to run yarn, art head test,
让我们尝试运行一下 "yarn hardhat test"
we get a whole bunch of errors,
我们得到了一大堆报错
and in VS code will actually go ahead and get these errors right from the linter.
在 VS Code 中，代码检查器其实也会发现这些错误
One of the trickiest things that you run into as a developer in this space
这个领域中的开发者所能遇到的最棘手的问题之一就是
is calling functions on contracts where those functions don't exist, or vice versa.
在合约上调用的函数不存在，或者反之亦然
We're not calling functions on contracts that do exist.
即，没有在已存在的合约上调用函数
Right now the typing for our contracts is just type contract,
目前我们合约的数据类型就是 "Contract" 类型
which isn't super helpful,
这其实没什么大用
because type contract doesn't necessarily have all the functions that we want it to have.
因为 "Contract" 类型可能并不包含我们所需的所有函数
We want our contracts to be of type contract,
我们当然希望合约类型是 "Contract"
but we want them to be of the type of our contract,
但我们更希望它们的类型可以是我们的合约
because if they're the type of our contract,
因为如果它们的类型是我们的合约
they can have all the functions that we want them to have.
它们就会拥有我们所需的所有函数
So to give our contracts the correct typing here,
所以为了给我们的合约提供正确的类型
we actually can use this tool called type chain, which gives our contracts correct typing
我们需要使用这个名为 "TypeChain" 工具，它可以给我们的合约提供正确的类型
type chain has a hardened plugin,
"TypeChain" 有一个 Hardhat 插件
which allows us to use type chain and TypeScript natively together,
这就允许我们能够原生地使用 "TypeChain" 和 "TypeScript"
type chain slash hard hat was one of these things that we already installed.
"typechain/hardhat" 就是我们已经安装好的工具之一
And to add it to our hard hat, we got to just go to the hard hat config,
要想把它添加进 Hardhat，我们只需要打开 "hardhat.config"
and add it in import at type chain slash arhat.
并添加 "import @typechain/hardhat"
Now once we import that in to our config, if we run yarn hardhat,
一旦我们把它导入进了 "config" 中，就可以运行 "yarn hardhat"
we now get a new task here called type chain,
现在我们获得了一个新的 task 名为 "typechain"
you read the description, it says generate type chain typings for compiled contracts,
可以读一下描述，它说的是：“为已编译的合约生成 Typechain 类型”
this will enable all of our contracts to have their own typing.
这将使我们的所有合约都拥有属于它们自己的类型
So we can have a simple storage variable of type simple storage contract,
这样我们就可以拥有一个 "SimpleStorage" 合约类型的 "simpleStorage" 变量了
which is much better, because we're always going to know exactly what we can do with each contract.
这样很好，因为这样我们就总是可以知道每个合约都能做什么了
To create this, we run yarn, arhat type chain.
要创建这个，我们需要运行 "yarn hardhat typechain"
And this is going to create a new folder called type chain slash types.
这样就会创建一个新的文件夹名为 "typechain-types"
With types for all of our contracts,
其中包含了我们所有的合约类型
you can even go into our simple storage sub Ts,
你甚至可以进入我们的 "SimpleStorage.ts"
which is going to have all the different functions and
它所具有的所有不同的函数
everything to do with our simple storage contract
以及你要用 "SimpleStorage" 合约所做的所有事
automatically coded into Typescript and JavaScript for us,
都会被自动生成为 TypeScript 和 JavaScript
which is incredibly helpful.
这真的很有用
And again, no, I haven't shown you what this is yet.
再次强调，尽管我还没有向你们详细说明
But in our dot Git ignore,
但在我们的 ".gitignore" 中
we usually want to add type chain and type chain dash types into our dot Git ignore so
通常要加上 "typechain" 以及 "typechain-types"
we don't push them up to GitHub.
我们不会把它们上传到 GitHub 上
Now back in our test, we're going to add the exact types of these different objects here.
现在回到我们的测试上，我们要给这些对象添加确切的类型
So we're going to import them from that folder that we just created.
因此我们要从刚刚创建的文件夹中导入它们
So we'll do import simple storage, comma, simple storage underscore underscore factory from dot dot slash types, ain slash types,
所以就是 "import  from "../typechain-types""
the simple storage factory is going to be simple storage factory
这个 "SimpleStorage factory" 就是 "simpleStorageFactory"
and then civil storage of course, is going to be simple storage.
而这个 "SimpleStorage" 当然就是 "simpleStorage" 了
So now when do let simple storage factory which is going to be of type, simple storage, underscore underscore factory,
所以我们要把 "let simpleStorageFactory" 指定为 "SimpleStorage__factory" 类型
and then simple storage, which is going to be of type simple storage contract.
而 "simpleStorage" 就会是 "SimpleStorage" 合约类型
And if we command clicked into simple storage,
如果我们使用 "Command + 点击" 的方法进入 "SimpleStorage"
once again, we can see all the contract functions that we know and love, are here.
就可以看到我们所熟悉的所有合约函数都在这里
In addition, we have all the functions of the actual contract itself.
此外，我们还可以获得实际的合约其本身的所有函数
Once we do that, we're pretty much good to go we just need to have a couple of new things here.
一旦完成这一步，基本上就已经可以开始了，只要在这里再添加一点东西
Get contract factory returns a type ethers dot contract factory.
"getContractFactory" 返回一个 "ethers.ContractFactory" 类型
So what we just need to do is we need to wrap this in a simple storage factory type.
因此，我们只需要将其包装进一个 "SimpleStorage__factory" 类型即可
So We'll just do a little wrap like this.
我们只要在这里简单包装一下
And we'll say, as simple storage, I'm just going to sort of factory.
然后写上 "as SimpleStorage__factory"
And that's good to go.
这就成了
Now that we've added all this, we can run yarn, Hardhead test.
现在我们已经添加好了所有的东西，就可以运行 "yarn hardhat test" 了
And boom, our test run is normal,
嘭！我们的测试运行正常
but with TypeScript and with this additional typing that makes our lives substantially substantially better.
有了 TypeScript 以及这些额外的类型，我们的工作将变得更加轻松
And that's going to be all you need to know for TypeScript,
这就是你需要知道的有关 TypeScript 的全部内容了
reusable, all of the branches have an optional TypeScript branch
通常，所有分支都会有一个可选的 TypeScript 分支
that you can use to reference to work with TypeScript.
你可以参考它们来使用 TypeScript 进行工作